Poindexter Family Record 1904-1974, n.d.
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Poindexter Family Record 1904-1974, n.d.
Thomas Balch Library
M 0112, VC 0073
.25 cubic feet.
The collection consists of a history of the Poindexter family written by Fielding Lewis Poindexter (1871-1944) entitled Poindexter Family Record and related material. The Poindexter Family Record traces the family from the seventeenth century to the generation of the "Poindexter Brothers and Sister": Miles Poindexter, Fielding Lewis Poindexter, Ernest Poindexter (1872-1938), William Anderson Poindexter (1874-1968), George Fauntleroy Poindexter (1876-1968), and Mary Macon Poindexter (1878-1956).
Lynn Condon, Leesburg, VA
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Lynn Condon, Leesburg, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2012.0110
Historical Information
The Poindexters were a prominent family in Virginia and Washington, DC in the early to mid-twentieth century. The most well-known member of the family was Miles Poindexter (22 April 1868 - 21 September 1946), one of six surviving children of William Bowyer Poindexter (27 November 1832 - 22 March 1917) and Josephine Reid Anderson (1838-1912). Miles Poindexter was a politician who served as a U.S. Representative and Senator from Washington. He was born in Memphis, Tennessee, but spent his childhood in Rockbridge County, Virginia, graduating with a law degree from Washington and Lee University in 1891. Shortly thereafter, he relocated to Walla Walla, Washington to practice law. Poindexter served in the US House of Representatives from 1909-1911, in the Senate from 1911-1923, and was appointed US Ambassador to Peru from 1923-1928. In 1928, he unsuccessfully tried to regain his Senate seat. Following his defeat, he retired to his home "Elk Cliff" in Rockbridge County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of a history of the Poindexter family written by Fielding Lewis Poindexter (1871-1944) entitled Poindexter Family Record and related material. The Poindexter Family Record traces the family from the seventeenth century to the generation of the "Poindexter Brothers and Sister": Miles Poindexter, Fielding Lewis Poindexter, Ernest Poindexter (1872-1938), William Anderson Poindexter (1874-1968), George Fauntleroy Poindexter (1876-1968), and Mary Macon Poindexter (1878-1956). The history includes clippings and photographs. The photographs have been separated and relocated in VC 0073. The collection also contains correspondence, the bulk of which is letters to Mary Clark (1909-1976) from her uncle, Miles Poindexter, and her father, William Anderson Poindexter; miscellaneous documents including the Daughters of the American Revolution application of Mrs. Kate Jennings Matheson (1879-1971), a speech delivered by Miles Poindexter on the floor of the Senate in 1919 on the subject of the League of Nations, and various notes on family history; as well as newspaper clippings. Newspaper clippings have been copied for preservation and removed.
Arrangement
Folder: Item
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Poindexter Family Record (M 112), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Ancestry Library Edition, Thomas Balch Library, http://www.ancestrylibrary.com/ (accessed July 2015).
Other Finding Aid
PastPerfect
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
Francis T.A. Junkin Collection, 1818-1918 (M 041), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Contents List
    - Poindexter Family Record "A Family History", n.d.
    - Correspondence, 1935 - 1967, n.d.
    - Documents,1919-1975
    - Clippings, 1904-1976, n.d.
    - vc_0073_0001 [Poindexter Family Record]; "Under the Old Walnut Tree," Dec. 20, 1932. Elk Cliff, Virginia
    - vc_0073_0002 [Poindexter Family Record; Elk Cliff, 1932]
    - vc_0073_0003 [Poindexter Family Record]; Elk Cliff, 5-30-32
    - vc_0073_0003_001 Negative; Elk Cliff, 5-30-32
    - vc_0073_0004 [Poindexter Family Record]; Graves of Wm B. Poindexter, Josephine A. Poindexter, Frances H. Poindexter, 5-30-32
    - vc_0073_0004_0001 Negative; Graves of Wm B. Poindexter, Josephine A. Poindexter, Frances H. Poindexter, 5-30-32
    - vc_0073_0005 [Poindexter Family Record]; "Montrose," Fincastle, VA-1913 (The grandson out in the yard) Would that you and I might have made this visit in the lifetime of our dear mother, accompanied by her.
    - vc_0073_0006 [Poindexter Family Record; two children, n.d.]
    - vc_0073_0007 [Poindexter Family Record]; "W.B.P.- June 3, 1913"
    - vc_0073_0008 [Poindexter Family Record; unidentified man, n.d.]
    - vc_0073_0009 [Poindexter Family Record; unidentified woman, n.d.]
    - vc_0073_0010 [Poindexter Family Record]; Thorn Hill, 5-30-1932
    - vc_0073_0010_0001 Negative; Thorn Hill, 5-30-1932
    - vc_0073_0011 [Poindexter Family Record]; Thorn Hill, 5-30-1932
    - vc_0073_0012 [Poindexter Family Record]; Cousin Frank Brockenbraugh and his family in Lexington, VA in 1909. L to R Frank, Miss Thomas Seumes "Lulu"- sister, ?. Louise Brock. Owens and daughter
    - vc_0073_0013 [Poindexter Family Record; unidentified man, n.d.]
    - vc_0073_0014 [Poindexter Family Record; unidentified girl, n.d.]
    - vc_0073_0015 [Poindexter Family Record]; F. Poindexter, Orlando, Fla, Mar. 26, 1927
    - vc_0073_0016 [Poindexter Family Record]; Elk Cliff, Dec. 20, 1932. Cervantes- the day before he went away to return no more.
    - c_0073_0017 [Poindexter Family Record]; By the side of our house-tomatoes on Charlotte's right: nasturtiums on her left' Wichita, Kans. July 9, 1904. This also is a good amateur picture.
    - vc_0073_0018 [Poindexter Family Record]; Kansas City, Kans. May 17, 1920. To my dear [illegible]
    - vc_0073_0019 [Poindexter Family Record; unidentified woman, n.d.]
    - vc_0073_0020 [Poindexter Family Record; unidentified man, n.d.]
    - vc_0073_0021 [Poindexter Family Record; unidentified man and woman with dogs, March 10, 1944]
    - vc_0073_0022 Elk Cliff, May 29, 1932
    - vc_0073_0022_0001 Negative; Elk Cliff, May 29, 1932
    - vc_0073_0023 [Unidentified men in yard], May 30, 1932
    - vc_0073_0023_0001 Negative; [Unidentified men in yard], May 30, 1932
    - vc_0073_0024 [Unidentified men at Elk Cliff], May 16, 1938]
    - vc_0073_0025 [Unidentified man at Elk Cliff], May 16, 1938
    - vc_0073_0026 [Unidentified man in yard], May 16, 1938
    - vc_0073_0027 [Unidentified men at Elk Cliff], May 16, 1938
    - vc_0073_0028 [Wm A. Poindexter] Peaks of Otter, Sept. 24, 1950
    - vc_0073_0029 [Wm A. Poindexter with dogs], 1951
    - vc_0073_0030 [Wm A. Poindexter with dogs], 1951
    - vc_0073_0031 [Wm A. Poindexter with dogs], 1952
    - vc_0073_0032 Taken in August 1956 at Mountain Home. L to R: Pete, Bat, your Dad and Teddy
    - vc_0073_0033 [Wm A. Poindexter] This picture was taken in our back yard, March 1957. W.A.P.
    - vc_0073_0034 Faunt Poindexter and wife Polly (2nd wife) and Wm A. Poindexter, July 1957
    - vc_0073_0035 Wm A. Poindexter, Jacksonville Beach, Fla. Jan 1957
    - vc_0073_0036 [Wm A. Poindexter] Taken Wed. Jan.15, 1958 in front yard at 511 Whitted
    - vc_0073_0037 David Russell Bryans, son of Russell Lindsey, Dec. 1962
    - vc_0073_0038 David Russell Bryans, son of Russell Lindsey, Dec. 1963
    - vc_0073_0039 This taken on Jan. 1, 1966. Was 91 Sept. 17, 1965
    - vc_0073_0040 Clark Bradford Currin, 1974
    - vc_0073_0041 David Bryan Wade with date for jr. prom, June 1974. David is son of Margaret Russell Lindsay
    - vc_0073_0042 Wm A. Poindexter and wife Ruby Stringer. Name of other person unknown, n.d.
    - vc_0073_0043 W. A. Poindexter, n.d.
    - vc_0073_0044 Negative [Unidentified woman and child by river's edge], n.d.
    - vc_0073_0045 Negative [Unidentified man, two women, and child on porch], n.d.
    - vc_0073_0056 Negative [Unidentified man], n.d.